CHYAVAN MYSORE CHANDRASHEKAR

chyavan.m.c@utexas.edu github.com/chyavan-mc • linkedin.com/in/chyavan-mc • (737) 275-8719

SUMMARY

A proficient Engineering and Business student in pursuit of a graduate degree in Business Analytics. Passionate about identifying business implications beyond data, communicating and articulating ideas to technical and non-technical audiences. Creative thinker with excellent troubleshooting skills and first-hand experience in Automation, Statistical Learning, Analytics, Full-stack Development, and Database Management. Passionate about experimenting with novel technologies and taking the initiative to implement ideas.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

May 2023

Master of Science, Business Analytics (GPA: 4/4)

• Coursework: Advanced Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Time Series Analysis, Data Visualization, Marketing Analytics, Database Management, Optimization, Demand Analytics & Pricing, Financial Management

JSS Science & Technology University

September 2020

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics & Communication (CGPA: 9.11/10)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Computer Languages: Python, SQL, R, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C#

Technologies & Tools: Git, Scikit-learn, NLTK, OpenCV, Gurobi, Angular, Spacy, Pandas, MS SQL Server, MySQL

Project Skills: Agile (Scrum, Jira, Kanban)

EXPERIENCE

Western Digital - Software Development Engineer, Bangalore, India

August 2020 - June 2022

- Owned a module of the automation and analytical reporting Software and delivered latency improvements resulting in performance boost of up to 300% in certain cases, functional and scalable code extensions, and front-end enhancements
- Devised SQL jobs, Windows Console Applications & Services, and back-end procedures to achieve communication between internal tools and process data periodically
- Took initiative to deliver significant UI features to improve and provide a consistent user experience for worldwide internal users for the testing process of Enterprise & Client SSDs

Western Digital - Software Development Intern, Bangalore, India

January 2020 - July 2020

• Initiated and developed an interface to automate workflow for Cadence schematics and hardware simulations resulting in more than 50% reduction of efforts and department-wide adoption

PROJECTS

A Cornucopia of Cereals - Crowdsourced Recommendation System

September 2022 - October 2022

• Scraped data of over 1500 cereals, including user reviews, and employed user requirements of desirable attributes or similar cereals to recommend the top-3 niche products based on results from Sentiment Analysis and Word2Vec Similarity

Austin MetroBike Trip Prediction

July 2022 - August 2022

• Performed multiple analyses on 1.69 million bike trips using parametric and non-parametric supervised machine learning models and predicted prospective trip volumes at MetroBike stations to provide supply management and marketing insights

Raga Detection

September 2019 - May 2020

• Led a team in a python-based project and analyzed audio data as a three-dimensional signal to extract musical notes as features and leveraged it in the application of live Raga (melodic mode) detection and correction for 200+ Carnatic Musical Ragas

LEADERSHIP

- Digital Media Lead Served as the Digital Media Lead for my undergraduate university's cultural festival 'Jayciana'
- Cultural Team Led my undergraduate university's cultural team of 50+ talented individuals into a national-level cultural competition, 'Antaragni' organized by IIT-Kanpur
- Developer Student Club by Google Orchestrated cloud study jams, workshops, and boot camps, while also serving as the lead for digital media and photography teams